

About me

I create modern *learning experiences*, be it online classes, in-person workshops or professional development courses. I designed an award-winning 3D Printer, taught in classrooms and ran hand-on workshops and MOOCs. I am a tinkerer and a DIY aficionado. I cherish the smell of freshly cut wood, but I am at home making things digital.

My approaches are steeped in cognitive sciences, design thinking, game-inspired learning, and both constructionist and constructivist approaches. I believe in curiosity, combining liberal arts with digital fabrication, and open-ended, learner-centered instruction.

Skills

Education & Tech

Instructional design and curriculum design, online and offline teaching, handson education, design thinking, constructionist learning, educational game design, MOOCs, iterative design processes.

English

Native-like with a penchant for crystal clear writing

Media Production

Videography, shooting and editing (Premiere Pro, Vegas, Final Cut Pro).
Analog and Digital
Photography (Lightroom, Photoshop). Graphics
(Illustrator, InDesign, Inkscape). Audio (Audition, Audacity).

Czech

Native with a taste for archaic and unusual phrases

"Making"

3D Printer Development, RepRap, Slicing Development (Simplify3D, Cura, Slic3r), CAD (Fusion360, TinkrCAD, OpenSCAD, Onshape), Arduino (Marlin), lasercutting, CNC, lathe, Git.

French

Intermediate with a soft spot for being understood

Education

Harvard Graduate School of Education

Master of Education: Technology, Innovation, and Education

Associate of Student Advisory Board | Winner of Harvard X Design Education Challenge

University of Virginia

Bachelor of Arts in Cognitive Sciences

Focus in Digital Humanities, New Media, and Cognitive Psychology | Dean's List

Northern Virginia Community College Associate Degree

Presidential Scholar and Dean's List | Award of High Academic Achievement

2009-2010

2010-2012

2012-2013

Experience

IMADE3D, LLC (USA)

Co-Creator; Captain of Design and Education

Co-founded a startup to teach general public, teachers, and students to assemble and use DIY 3D Printers as a learning experience. Used design thinking and learning theories to create the award-winning educational 3D Printer "JellyBOX" (modeled in (Fusion360, AutoCAD, Illustrator). JellyBOX has been awarded "Best for Schools" by Make Magazine in 2017 and 2019. I also developed the IMADE3D educational concept of Hands-on Builds, created an online documentation (Dozuki, Docsify, Discourse, Github Pages), shot and edited instructional videos (Premiere Pro), customized forks of open source firmware and software (Arduino-Marlin and Cura), designed and administered the website (Wordpress), managed e-shop (Magento 2), and oversaw the online community.

www.imade3d.com

2015-present

Avenues the World School (online, China) 3D Printer Design and Learning Process Advisor

2019

Supported a group of international high school students through designing and building their own 3D printers; provided design critiques and guidance in both physical and software aspects of the design process.

HEP Haute École Pédagogique (Switzerland) Instructor of 2D and 3D Computer-Aided Design

2018

Developed and taught two year-long professional development courses (a part of the PIRACEF program) to groups of about 15 students. One course was on 2D CAD (using Illustrator and Inkscape), and the second was on 3D CAD (using Fusion 360). Created a github pages based course website with pre-recorded design walkthroughs.

Emerson College School of Communication (USA) Human-Centered Design Facilitator & Senior Project Manager

2013-2015

Over the course of a year, lead a cross-departmental, diverse group of faculty to re-thing and re-align the structure and programming of the entire School of Communication in the spirit of design thinking. Analysed the ed-tech space, and provided resources and activities to have the faculty explore and experience current communication and educational technology trends. Designed and managed online spaces to share findings and interact asynchronously. Run an internal mini-conference on technological trends including a design thinking workshop.

Emerson College (USA)

2015

Teaching Assistant for Communication Management Course

Provided feedback and guidance on graduate students' final year's Communication Management projects. Managed class's Canvas site including forum and submissions and google docs integrations. Secured video recordings of sessions, and provided general IT support. Led classes on various subjects.

HarvardX = Harvard branch of EdX (USA) MOOC Researcher

2014

A part of a team assembled to compare and contrast MOOC courses from various providers to identify the best course design and community management practices. Produced an internal document outlining the state of the art and proposing innovative approaches to teaching online across disciplines.

University of Liverpool Online Courses (UK) Instructional Designer & Curriculum Writer

2013-2014

Worked with an international team of content experts to re-design and re-write existing online courses in an MBA program to fit into a new school-wide pedagogical model aimed at increasing interactivity and students' collaboration.

HFR Veritas Education (China) Curriculum Designer and Content Expert

2014

Co-created curricula for after-school programs in Creative Problem Solving and Critical thinking for a local start-up in Shanghai, China. Reviewed and compiled existing literature and trends in teaching creativity. Spearheaded human-centered design practices in developing the coursework - held multiple sessions with a selection of future Chinese students to test activities and align the curriculum with the needs and expectations of the regional audience. Delivered both instructional activities for students, and teaching manual for instructors.

Center for Talented Youth of Johns Hopkins University (USA) Teaching Assistant of Cognitive Psychology

2011-2012

Prepared and taught college level lessons on various topics of Cognitive Psychology to class of 15 gifted teenagers. Supervised students' learning with an interactive suite of cognitive psychology experiments. Supplied students with lab report templates and critical thinking question, and provided constructive feedback on performance.

Northern Virginia Community College (USA) ESOL and English Writing Tutor

2010

Held one-on-one tutoring sessions with college students of all English proficiencies (including native speakers). Worked with students to improve both their grammar and writing style. Specialized on American academic writing structure and style.

Projects

Design 101 MOOC, Iversity (online) Community Meta-Manager and Lead

2014

Lead an international community of -40 volunteers to manage a vibrant community of 40,000 students (about 10,000 active) in Iversity's Design 101 MOOC. Imagined and spearheaded ways to make this technologically and humanly possible. Heavily experimented with social and communication media (Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest, Google+, Hangouts, Slack, forum, email...) to keep the students engaged. http://iversity.org/en/courses/design-101-or-design-basics

Education Design Shop at MIT (USA) Co-Organizer

2014

Together with the founder Jess, developed and ran a 2-day hackathon in Design Thinking for Educational Policy for educators, students, policy makers, and designers at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology. Co-designed the website and print materials, shot video interviews with 'inspiring experts' (including the Massachusetts Secretary of Education, dr. Malone), developed scoring rubric, planned the activities... and anything else that was needed.

http://edudesignshop.mit.edu

HyperStudio at MIT (USA) Digital Annotation Data Visualizations Designer

2013

HyperStudio is a digital humanities lab at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology. I used annotation data from HyperStudio's Annotation Studio to design and code interactive visualizations of users' reading paths using Processing and D3.js. Additionally, I built a user case study to streamline the UX and UI of the web app Also presented the work under the title "Temporal Aspect of Annotating" at "Convergence @Harvard" conference.

Filip Goč I filip@imade3d.com +1 202 643 4547